We will see this enormous growth, this coiling of the embryo.
この巨大な成長、胚の巻き込みを見ていきましょう。
Here we only see the vitelline cavity.
ここでは卵黄嚢だけが見えます。
Above, we have cut the amniotic cavity.
上では羊膜腔を切断しています。
Longitudinal growth, flexion.
縦方向の成長、屈曲。
I see my nervous system there.
ここに私の神経系が見えます。
I see the somites and I see the vascular systems.
体節と血管系が見えます。
I'm going to ask you to pay attention to an opening here.
ここに開口部があることに注目していただきたいと思います。
which is called the future opening of the intraembryonic coelom.
これは将来の胚内体腔の開口部と呼ばれるものです。
You see, you have to imagine it here.
ご覧の通り、ここに想像する必要があります。
We find it here, there, you see,
ここにそれが見つかります、ほら、
which will later integrate this external coelom into an internal coelom.
それは後にこの外体腔を内体腔に統合します。
The enormous growth of my system causes my two primitive endocardial tubes
私のシステムの巨大な成長により、私の2つの原始心内膜管は
to approach the median line
正中線に近づきます。
because they have a differential growth rate,
なぜなら、それらは異なる成長速度を持っているからです。
notochord, which influences.
脊索が影響を与えます。
this information, approximation of my two endocardial tubes, and a part
この情報、私の2つの心内膜管の接近、そして一部が
here above,
ここの上部に、
it will become my intestine as we saw, and around here, it will form what we call
それは私たちが以前見たように私の腸になり、そしてここでそれは形成します。
the intraembryonic cavity, it will form what we call, not
私たちが呼ぶもの、
the peritoneal cavity,
腹膜腔、
but at that stage, higher up, the pericardial cavity, the vitelline vesicle,
しかし、この段階では、より上部に、心膜腔、卵黄嚢、
which will
それは
come closer, form you.
近づいて、あなたを形成します。
the upper part of the intestine.
腸の上部。
Then, the approximation of my two endocardial tubes, here,
次に、私の2つの心内膜管の接近がここにあります。
to form the developing cardiac tube area.
発達中の心臓管の領域を形成するためです。
So, we see it not only like this, but also like this.
したがって、私たちはこれをこのように見るだけでなく、このように見ることもできます。
I showed you a movement where it does this.
私はそれがこのように動くのを見せました。
Now we see the same movement, like this.
今、私たちは同じ動きをこのように見ます。
So, it's a combination of the two approaching my median line.
したがって、それは私の正中線に近づく2つの組み合わせです。
like this, but at the same time, I have a movement where
このように、しかし同時に、私は動きを持っています。
the brain does this.
脳がこれを行います。
We could say that it is a cardio-pleuro-peritoneal cavity,
それは心臓-胸膜-腹膜腔であると言うことができます。
but which will then be completely integrated, separated by my diaphragm,
しかし、それは後に完全に統合され、私の横隔膜によって分離されます。
we have a cardio-pleuro-peritoneal cavity, and then only pericardial.
私たちは心臓-胸膜-腹膜腔を持ち、そして純粋に心膜腔を持ちます。
The very first movement, on a specific, energetic level, is at the level of the
最初の動きは、特定の、エネルギー的な平面では、尾骨のレベルにあります。
coccyx.
尾骨。
At the same time, I have this whole migration phase, I have this whole synchronicity of development.
同時に、私はこの移行段階全体を持ち、この発達の同期全体を持っています。
Now, in its dynamics, I find myself here, it's at the same time that I have this
今、そのダイナミクスの中で、私はここにいます、それは私がこれを持っているのと同時にです。
flexion phase of the embryo and that I have this approximation towards my median line like
胚の屈曲相で、私の正中線に向かってこの接近があるように
The thumbs, it's this meeting, it's the first movement at the level of the heart.
親指は、この出会い、心臓の最初の動きです。
The heart, it's a sagittal view, it's there, it meets like this, we agree.
心臓は、矢状面から見ると、そこにあり、このように出会います。同意しますね。
The heart wants to develop.
心臓は発達したいと思っています。
Where does it have space?
どこにスペースがありますか？
It no longer has space behind.
後ろにはもうスペースがありません。
It doesn't have much space to the left or right.
左にも右にも大きなスペースはありません。
It only has space in front.
前方にしかスペースがありません。
And within the heart itself, it will have its own fulcrum.
そして、心臓自体の中に、独自の支点を持つことになります。
This is the front, this is the back.
これが前で、これが後ろです。
A sagittal section.
矢状断。
So it develops forward.
だから、それは前方に発達します。
It does this, what we call the looping movement of the heart.
それはこれを行います。心臓のルーピング運動と呼ばれるものです。
This is phase 2, let's say.
これはフェーズ2と言えるでしょう。
It continues to develop,
それは発達し続け、
which means that it will form a third level here, like this.
その結果、ここにこのように第3のレベルが形成されます。
This means that the space between the ventricular system and the atrium
つまり、心室系と心房の間の空間が、
becomes a fulcrum which means that the ventricle which is above
支点となり、その結果、上にある心室が、
will become below in relation to my system.
私のシステムに対して下になります。
It will make an inversion movement, like that.
このように反転運動をします。
First movement, it's a movement.
最初の動きは、動きです。
approximation towards my median line and a meeting.
私の正中線への接近と出会い。
Second movement, it makes a movement like that.
2番目の動きは、このように動きます。
Third movement that will appear,
現れる3番目の動きは、
it is related to the development process of my peritoneal cavity.
私の腹膜腔の発達プロセスに関連しています。
You remember, at some point, the development of the liver
覚えていますか、ある時点で、肝臓の発達は、
will cause a tilt on the movement
動きに傾きが生じ、
and we will have the omental bursa which will displace my left bronchus,
そして、大網の空洞が私の左気管支を移動させ、
a little higher here, compared to my right, linked to the process.
私の右よりも少し高い位置に、プロセスに関連して。
axial which we call symmetry breaking.
対称性の破綻と呼ばれる軸方向の。
So I will have a movement
だから、私は動きを持つでしょう。
of development, this time forward,
今回は前方への発達ですが、
but also
しかしまた、
to the left. I have
左へ。私は、
a double tilt like that.
このように二重の傾きがあります。
For now, what we remember is especially
今のところ、私たちが覚えているのは、主に、
the approximation towards my median line of my heart,
私の心臓の正中線への接近、
the development forward
前方への発達、
and at the same time a development to the left.
そして同時に左方への発達です。
I will have
私は持つでしょう。
the whole sinusoidal system
tout le système sinusoïde
of the liver that will go up afterwards.
du foie qui va se mettre vers le haut après.
By this tilt, like that.
Par cette bascule, comme ça.
So, first movement.
Donc, premier mouvement.
Second movement, it will be related to my tilt.
Deuxième mouvement, ce sera en rapport avec ma bascule.
Third movement, which will organize my large vessels all above.
Troisième mouvement, qui va organiser mes gros vaisseaux tout au-dessus.
If you look at a heart, you see that it is really held here by a caval axis.
Si  tu  regardes  un  cœur,  tu  vois  qu 'il  est  vraiment  maintenu  ici  par  un  axe  cavale.
It maintains itself in relation to this vascular plane, with a greater development here.
Il se maintient par rapport à ce plan vasculaire, avec un développement plus important ici.
And my axis here, like this.
Et mon axe ici, comme ceci.
It's a balance between the thoracic part.
C'est un équilibre entre la partie thoracique.
The abdominal part here and the lower visceral part.
La partie abdominale ici et la partie viscérale basse.
A very important movement between the heart here, I take under the
Un  mouvement  très  important  entre  le  cœur  ici,  je  prends  sous  l
stomach there, and there I have the liver.
'estomac  là,  et  là  j 'ai  le  foie.
The liver in its development, it will do this.
Le foie dans son développement, ça va faire ça.
A very important reference point to rebalance.
Un point de référence très important à rééquilibrer.
I put myself here and I see if the hepatic movement comes towards me, if I exaggerate
Je  me  mets  ici  et  je  regarde  si  le  mouvement  hépatique  vient  vers  moi,  si  j 'exagère
like this or like this.
comme  ceci  ou  comme  ceci.
I put myself like this and I watch the movement that starts.
Je me mets comme ceci et je regarde le mouvement qui part.
So no problem here, this liver wants to go well in its development movement, it
Donc  pas  de  problème  ici,  ce  foie  veut  bien  aller  dans  son  mouvement  de  développement,  il
is not in retreat.
n 'est  pas  en  retrait.
It stops a tiny bit here, I have a tiny stop now here, I
Il  s 'arrête  un  tout  petit  peu  ici,  j 'ai  un  tout  petit  arrêt  maintenant  ici,  je
leave it here.
le  laisse  ici.
Now if I put myself at the level of the heart, the heart in its development will do the opposite.
Maintenant si je me mets au niveau du cœur, le cœur dans son développement il va faire l'inverse.
I come here, I exaggerate my movements, it does this.
Je viens ici, j'exagère mes mouvements, ça fait ceci.
Development is a developmental movement.
Le développement c'est un mouvement développemental.
However, there is a trajectory, there is like an imprint.
Par contre il y a une trajectoire, il y a comme une empreinte.
I put myself on the embryonic imprint, you see.
Je me mets sur l'empreinte embryonnaire, tu vois.
I'm just going to go where it wants, and that's where the point of silence is.
Je vais juste aller là où il veut, et c'est là où il y a le point de silence.
For example here, I want to put it again, it could go a little further, you see.
Par exemple ici, je veux bien mettre de nouveau, elle pourrait aller un peu plus loin, tu vois.
So it's as if someone here is going to move forward there, but at some point, something is holding her back.
Donc  c 'est  comme  si  c 'est  quelqu 'un  ici  qui  va  avancer  là,  mais  à  un  moment  donné,  il  y  a  quelque  chose  qui  la  freine.
So, we have to help her.
Voilà, donc il faut l'aider.
All this is the organization of my heart, which is strongly organized by my liver.
Tout ça, c'est l'organisation de mon cœur, qui est fortement organisée par mon foie.
So understand the importance of the liver.
Donc bien comprendre l'importance du foie.
In biological embryology,
Dans l'embryologie biologique,
dynamic, we don't impose. I don't reject facial curves, I don't reject the fluidic
dynamique,  on  n 'impose  pas.  Je  ne  rejette  pas  les  coudes  faciales,  je  ne  rejette  pas  le  côté
side, I don't reject structural visceral techniques or others. I will
fluidique, je ne rejette pas les techniques structurelles viscérales ou autres. Je vais
adapt according to what I feel in the present moment. But the therapeutic force,
m'adapter en fonction de ce que je ressens dans le moment présent. Mais la force thérapeutique,
it is there. The most beautiful power where it can best emerge, is this force that
elle  est  là.  La  plus  belle  puissance  où  elle  peut  le  mieux  émerger,  c 'est  cette  force  qu
we
'on
find in the meeting of my two neutrals. It's not always easy to have both
retrouve dans la rencontre de mes deux neutres. Ce n'est pas toujours évident d'avoir les deux
neutrals. However, if you succeed, it's fantastic. But sometimes, we can do a
ニュートラルです。しかし、もしそれができれば素晴らしいことです。しかし、時には、
structural technique in relation to what I said.
私が言ったことに関して、構造的なテクニックを行うこともできます。
I listen or I don't listen, it's up to you to choose where you feel enlightened in biodynamic osteopathy.
私が聞くか聞かないかは、生体力学的オステオパシーにおいて、あなたが輝いていると感じる場所を選ぶことです。これらのプロセス、これらの再生プロセスに入ると、
When we enter into these processes, these regeneration processes use these
これらの発生学的運動が利用されます。ここでは治療は行いませんでしたが、治療プロセスで現れる可能性のある発生学的運動をお見せしました。
embryonic
これらの
movements. Here, I haven't done therapy, I've shown you the embryonic developmental movements
胚性運動。ここでは治療は行いませんでしたが、潮によって与えられる治療プロセスで現れる可能性のある発生学的運動をお見せしました。
that can appear in therapeutic processes
潮によって与えられる治療プロセスで現れる可能性のある発生学的運動。しかし、私がいる周波数を認識するだけで十分です。
Sometimes, I'm going to show you a movement. Be careful, I'm not...
時々、動きをお見せします。注意してください、私は...
not in the therapeutic process, I'm showing you the imprint of the embryo's development.
治療プロセスではありません。胚の発生の痕跡をお見せしています。
embryo.
胚の。
We rarely touch a heart first. The heart forms by the echo of the periphery.
実際、最初に心臓に触れることはめったにありません。心臓は周辺のエコーによって形成されます。
The heart is something that is extremely powerful because it receives very important
心臓は非常に強力なものです。なぜなら、それは非常に重要な情報を受け取るからです。
information from the neural crest. The heart receives electrical
神経堤によって非常に重要な情報を受け取ります。心臓は、
information,
電気的な情報を受け取ります。
even more powerful on a neurological level. That means that...
神経学的な観点から見ても、さらに強力です。つまり、
that we can learn to feel the heart at a distance,
遠くから心臓を感じることを学ぶことができます。
where the heart is felt at a distance.
または、心臓が遠くから感じられる場所。
It has a power, it has a radiance.
それは力と輝きを持っています。
They measured that it was up to 5 meters minimum from the person.
彼らは、それが人から最低5メートル離れていることを測定しました。
And probably that is also linked to this neural crest here.
そして、おそらくそれはここにある神経堤にも関連しています。
It's an electrical power.
それは電気的な力です。
It is there, on the venous plane,
それは、静脈の観点から、
that there will be a development called the venous sinus of the heart.
心臓の静脈洞と呼ばれる発達があるでしょう。
And in this venous sinus will appear
そして、この静脈洞には、
the union of my cardinal valves, of my umbilical valves
私の主静脈、私の臍帯静脈の結合が現れます。
and right in the center of my vitelline valves,
そして、私の卵黄静脈のまさに中央に、
which will undergo a lot of remodeling that we will study when we see the venous system in detail.
静脈系を詳細に見るときに研究する多くの再編成を受けるでしょう。
The heart has a facial environment, has its own electricity for its heartbeat.
心臓には顔面環境があり、心拍のための独自の電気を持っています。
heartbeat.
心臓の。
This electricity was not enough to maintain the heart in its proper function
この電気だけでは、心臓をその正しい機能に維持するには不十分でした。
and that it was dependent in its functioning.
そして、その機能は依存していました。
of the entire facial environment, the sternopericardial ligament,
すべての顔面環境、胸骨心膜靭帯、
phrenicopericardial, vertebropericardial,
横隔膜心膜、椎骨心膜、
and up to the aorta, etc., suspended up to the pharyngeal tubercle.
そして上部まで、大動脈など、咽頭結節まで吊り下げられています。
This system supported the rhythmicity of the heart.
このシステムは心臓のリズムを支えていました。
In the system, there is a closed oscillation system, I forgot a high,
システムには閉じた振動システムがあります。私は「高」を忘れました。
and in the way it is built, when we look at the structure,
そして、それが構築されている方法、構造を見ると、
tissue molecular of this attachment system, by the beating heart, the tissue
この付着システムの分子組織は、鼓動する心臓によって、組織は、
around
その周りにある
will undergo a stretching movement, but
伸びる動きをしますが、
the way it is built, you see, by
その構築方法、ほら、
these fibers, it's a bit like if I had an elastic here and an elastic
これらの繊維によって、まるでここにゴムバンドがあり、あそこにゴムバンドがあるかのようです。
there.
あそこにゴムバンドがあったとします。
I pull here, because the elastic brings me back there, by the beating of the heart.
心臓の鼓動によって、ゴムバンドが私をそこへ引き戻すので、私はここを引っ張ります。
I pull here, but the more I pull, the more I pull.
私はここを引っ張りますが、引っ張れば引っ張るほど、より強く引っ張られます。
force that brings me back. But the more I pull this way, the more I have another
私を引き戻す力。しかし、ここを引っ張れば引っ張るほど、別の力が働きます。
force that brings me back too.
私をまた引き戻す力。
This means that in the very structuring of the tissue fascia
それは、心膜の組織筋膜の構造そのものの中に、
of the pericardium that supports
心臓を支える心膜の組織筋膜の構造そのものの中に、
the heart, the heart itself is supported in its rhythmicity by its facial environment.
心臓は、そのリズム性を周囲の筋膜環境によって支えられているということです。
The entire facial system of the heart that is here around can influence the rhythm
ここにある心臓の筋膜系全体が、心臓のリズムに影響を与える可能性があります。
of the heart.
心臓のリズムに影響を与える可能性があります。
The importance of freedom.
自由の重要性。
structural of the cardiac environment.
心臓周囲の構造的自由の重要性。
That's where I think we have a direct action.
ここに直接的な作用があると思います。
Systole, diastole, you have to see the heart as an octopus.
収縮期、拡張期、心臓はタコのように見るべきです。
The aortic arch and the entire trunk up to these junctions
大動脈弓と、これらの結合部までの幹全体が、
here.
ここにあります。
A big octopus like that, but not just the body,
このような大きなタコですが、体だけでなく、
but right into its tentacles, you see.
触手まで、ほら。
It goes very deep into my belly, I can feel it in my throat,
お腹の奥深くまで届き、喉で感じることができ、
I can feel it in my feet.
足で感じることができます。
You can feel it in your fingers.
指で感じることができます。
This means that a hip destabilization can destabilize the heart.
それは、股関節の不安定化が心臓を不安定化させる可能性があることを意味します。
There are people who have arrhythmias and we don't know why.
不整脈を持つ人々がいますが、その原因は不明です。
And in fact, if you free the hips, you free them here.
実際、股関節を解放すると、ここも解放されます。
There is a whole relationship through the endothelium.
内皮を介した全体的な関係があります。